## **ALMAZ DOLUBAEV**

Washington, DC

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dolubaev/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/varan2030">https://github.com/varan2030</a>
Email: <a href="mailto:almaz@dolubaev.com">almaz@dolubaev.com</a>

Portfolio: https://www.dolubaev.com

# FULL STACK JAVASCRIPT WEB DEVELOPER

I'm a front-end and back-end web developer, working with diverse project teams all the way from mockup to rollout and maintenance. My banking and entrepreneurial experiences greatly contribute to analytical and problem-solving tasks, thus making me an efficient and a creative web developer.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript, React, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, AXIOS, Bootstrap, Bulma, HTML, CSS;

Back-end: Node.js, REST, Express.js, SQL, noSQL, Sequelize, Mongoose;

Cloud: Heroku, AWS (Rekognition, IAM); Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase;

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Postman, Robo 3T, Git, Github;

APIs: Google, Yahoo Weather, Ticketmaster, Eventful, Petfinder, Twitter, Spotify, OMDB.

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

SUPERIORAPPS, LLC 3/17 – present

Front-End Web Developer

- Develop front end of the Facility Management Information System (FIMS). Utilize HTML5 and CSS3 techniques, backed by jQuery and JavaScript, to enable optimum user experience throughout the application
- Write application code to interact with APIs, Web Services using AJAX, JSON
- Participate in implementing Enterprise-level multi-tier applications; design, implement and maintain UI and application interface

#### APPLICATIONS

## PERSONA (http://persona-com.herokuapp.com)

- Developed the application, which helps restaurants to individualize their customer experience, thus strengthening their competitive advantage in providing more personalized customer service;
- Utilized Amazon Web Services (AWS) APIs to recognize customers' faces (AWS Rekognition)
- Used back-end frameworks to build server-side software in Node.js, like Express.js, Mongoose, AWS SDK. Created the schema and wrote middleware to store the data in MongoDB;
- Designed and built front-end by using REACT, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

## TASK MANAGER (https://taskmanager-com.herokuapp.com)

- Developed the application, which allows to create, update and delete tasks
- Created a task logger with MySQL, Node.js, Express.js and Sequelize
- Designed and built front-end by using Template literal, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

## ANIMAL KINGDOM (https://varan2030.github.io/TravelLion)

- Developed the application matches pets that need homes with people best suited to take care of them!
- Technologies: Petfinder API, MySQL, Node.js, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Bulma, GIT, GitHub

## TRIVIA GAME (https://varan2030.github.io/TriviaGame)

- Developed a Mary Christmas Trivia Game playable in the browser;
- Used JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Sprites, Bootstrap, game logic.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**ENTREPRENEUR** 2010–2016

• Founded a variety of food/consumer based initiatives including: agricultural enterprise, dairy and meat products wholesale and retail chain.

**BANK POZITIV** 2009–2010

Internal Auditor

• Audited the bank's business processes, evaluated the efficacy of risk management procedures, identified fraud and theft cases, and improved internal control and governance practices.

## NATIONAL BANK OF KYRGYZ REPUBLIC

2003-2010

Promoted from Inspector to Team Leader (Banking Supervision Division)

- Inspected the largest and complex banks in Kyrgyzstan;
- Led complete on-site bank audits. Analyzed commercial bank financial statements for compliance with prudential requirements;
- Managed a team of 12 inspectors and determined a scope of on-site work for each inspector;
- Worked together with IT specialists to develop regulatory reports.

## **EDUCATION**

#### GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY

2017-2018

Full Stack Web Development Certificate Program

## ACADEMY OF MANAGEMENT UNDER THE PRESIDENT OF KYRGYZ REPUBLIC

2002-2004

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

## INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF KYRGYZSTAN

1999-2002

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, majoring in Finance and Banking (with Honours)

## **AWARDS**

2008 Award for extraordinary performance and exemplary banking supervision leadership

2006 Award for outstanding professionalism and contribution to the development of the banking

system of the Kyrgyz Republic